Steve Maciaszek

Cupertino, CA (650) 793-8244 stevemaciaszek@comcast.net

Overview

Well-rounded IT professional with experience as both a team and individual contributor on web application development projects. In-depth knowledge of the software development lifecycle, including requirements gathering, concept design, planning, prototyping, development, testing, and implementation.

Technical Summary

React, Angular, Vue, Node, HTML5, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, React Native, Jest, Git

Professional Experience

Ul Developer, Grid Dynamics, Santa Clara, CA 01/2020 - 4/2021

- Developed, maintained and refactored React code for leading banking application. Experience with full lifecycle of each project, from spec review and coding to unit testing and deployment.
- Wrote effective and well-tested reliable code in React, performed code reviews. Worked closely with Quality Assurance professionals to ensure the best possible experience for our client.

Software Developer, Cupertino, CA

2015 - present

Worked as a contract developer with great teams to build out web and mobile software applications. Responsible for creating efficient design and development, and end-to-end application integration using React, Vue, and Angular.

- Developed applications using React for the logical implementation part of the client side and Node, coupled with Express, for the back-end.
- Built-out new product pages and modules for both web and mobile platforms for the online store for new product releases for both web and mobile. Implemented key features within the discussions.apple.com. Developed an internal dashboard using Angular to streamline communication and efficiency for the internal customer support.
- Collaborated closely with global team(s) in software integration and problem solving: identifying and mitigating risks, clarifying questions, eliminating impediments
- Worked as a developer at: Yahoo, Apple, SAP, Druva, Aurea Software, and Silicon Valley Bank.

*UI Developer, eH*ealth, Mountain View, CA 10/2012 – 12/2014

Successfully built-out and enhanced a number of eHealth web properties using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, including the corporate website and mobile application, resource center, Medicare, and Affordable Care Act site.

- Lead Engineer for the website redesign, beginning with prototyping, and moving all the way to implementation of specific pages and components.
- Developed a consumer price index using HighCharts, Google Charts, and D3 to allow users to track and analyze health insurance savings and to visualize future health plan offerings and savings.
- Worked as the Team Lead Developer on the front-end for the Affordable Care Act application using Node, Backbone, MongoDB.
- Developed a user Resource Center built with WordPress to assist users with their current health offerings and to boost overall retention.

Web Developer/UI Prototyper, IMVU, Mountain View CA

10/2011 - 8/2012

As the Lead UI Developer, was tasked to prototype new features for all portions of the new site redesign.

- Worked seamlessly with the UI Design team to develop prototypes, new features, and functionality to build pieces
 of the new application. Developed user-interface elements in HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Conducted daily user tests to refine the prototype to enhance the products based on user feedback, then modified code for efficiency and customer satisfaction.

Sr. Web Developer, Uptake, Palo Alto, CA

1/2011 - 10/2011

As a Senior Developer, successfully managed a full website redesign for a leading travel recommendations website. Worked comfortably in an agile environment that also included expanding and enhancing a robust Ruby on Rails application.

Sr. UI Developer, Red Oak Technology, onsite at Apple, Cupertino, CA 01/2009 – 01/2011

As a developer for the Apple Online Store, built out the pages, modules, and components and also participated in numerous new product introductions.

- Developed landing pages, store pages, modules, and components for store.apple.com.
- Fixed localization issues with pages and modules, as well as, related CMS tasks.
- Handled site-wide bug fixes and enhancements for both desktop and mobile platforms.

UI Developer, Ooma, Palo Alto, CA 3/2008 – 11/2008

As the on-site Lead Developer, was responsible for the Ooma web application, which included providing guidance for diverse and remote teams to keep the teams streamlined, on schedule, and within budget. This was developed using dynamic PHP pages, while adhering to strict HTML and CSS compliance standards.

Founder/Web Developer, Piczo, San Francisco, CA

2002 - 2007

Founding team member (employee #2) for Piczo, which was a social sharing and website builder tool.

- Took the lead development role for the front-end user interface for this on-line site builder and social networking site for teenagers worldwide, garnering over 2.5 billion page views and 12 million unique visitors a month.
- Worked with investors to garner 5th Round Series D funding in addition to managing/building the Engineering Development team, securing office space, and managing the logistics of running an office.

Web Programmer, The Dialog Corporation, Mountain View, CA 2001 - 2002

As a Cold Fusion programmer, developed core sections of the company-wide Intranet to streamline company processes and enhance worker-productivity.

Education

CSU, Chico. Bachelor of Arts, Information and Communication Studies.

Major: Instructional Technology. Minor: Psychology